在这里，我们将学习如何区分向量。并按比例
Here, we will learn to distinguish between vectors. And scale as
向量是同时具有一个数量级和一个数字的对象
vectors are objects that have both a magnitude, a single number
还有方向，
and direction,
而比例尺只有一个量级。
whereas scale as have only a magnitude.
让我们看看每个例子。
Let's see some examples of each.
某物的长度是标量，
The length of something is a scalar,
因为这只是数量级，
because it's just the magnitude,
拉力某人拉动某物所施加的力量
a force exerted by someone pulling something
是一个向量，
is a vector,
因为我们关心力量的力量，
because we care about the strength of the force,
大小，
the magnitude,
以及力的作用方向
and the direction in which the forces acting
温度。
temperature.
这是一个定标器。
It's a scaler.
如果我们在天气图上显示温度，
If we display temperature on a weather map,
在空间中每个点的温度值不同的地方，
where the value of the temperature is different at each point in space,
这是一个标量场
this is a scalar field
相比之下。
in comparison.
这张风的天气图，
This weather map of wind,
或者空间中每个点的风速值，
or the value of the wind velocity at each point in space,
由矢量表示
is represented by a vector
是一个向量场。
is a vector field.